vadim@manokhin.tech

ABOUT

A Full Stack Application Developer with experience working as a UI, UX, and QA engineer, systems administrator. Current career goals and objectives include designing and implementing enterprise-scale systems, minimizing costs and maximizing performance of software solutions, improving operational efficiency of organizations, learning new technologies to overcome business challenges, empowering and leading effective teams of engineers. Interested in analytics, finance, and investing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Babson College

Application Developer

Babson Park, MA Apr 2014 – present

- Design, develop, and support complex dynamic cross-browser web applications using ACF/Fusebox, Java, PHP/Drupal, C#/.NET, JS/CSS along with their popular frameworks/libraries in production systems that serve enterprise customers while handling an increasing growth of requests, users, and functionalities;
- Create enterprise-scale integration solutions for a variety of systems using SOAP and RESTful web services, APIs, ETL tools, MS SQL Server;
- Work with, use, and help configure Salesforce.com (Sales/HEDA cloud), Informatica (ICS, DI, APIs), Workday (HR, Recruitment), JIRA (on prem), SharePoint, Neoload, and other technologies.

Recent projects:

- Designing and implementing a SFDC-based alumni engagement platform that serves a community of over 50,000 Babson alumni around the world;
- Redesigning of the online giving site (<u>bab.sn/givenow</u>) into a single-page web app, resulting in an improved UX which increased number of donations - one of the primary sources of income for the college;

Babson College Software Developer Co-op / Application Developer Intern

Babson Park, MA May 2012 – Apr 2014

- Created and maintained dynamic web applications for the Babson Portal a platform of over 150 custom written tools with 2,000,000+ lines of code; researched, proposed, and integrated new software solutions;
- Wrote custom two-way web services and data feeds to integrate internal data stores and systems with a variety of third party applications and tools;
- Developed custom system workflows (XML), services, and events (JellyScript) in JIRA, performed system administration of the Atlassian stack (JIRA, Confluence) including data back-up, indexing, and restoring, system troubleshooting, patching, etc.

Projects included:

- Developing a single page web app that streamlined the annual faculty reporting of student opinion surveys, significantly reducing time and paper required to create the reports;
- Automating the semiannual e-mail send-out of personalized print statistics as part of a print awareness campaign, increasing efficient printing practices and awareness of sustainability initiatives, resulting in several thousand dollars of reduced costs.

vadim@manokhin.tech

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced knowledge of ACF, t-SQL, JS, CSS, XML/HTML, ETL tools (Informatica, SSIS), SOAP and RESTful web services, JIRA, Confluence.

Intermediate knowledge of C/C#, .NET, Java, PHP, Drupal, Salesforce.com/SOQL/APEX/Visualforce, Workbench, git, SharePoint, Workday, VSS.

Familiarity with Assembly (MASM), Python, Perl, Objective C/Swift, most flavors of shell scripting, Selenium, CrazyEgg, Mendix, Neoload, Laserfiche, webRTC, webVR, MEAN stack.

EDUCATION

Babson College

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business Master of Business Administration (MBA)

- Business Analytics and Finance concentration, Investments track

Babson Park, MA

May 2016 - present

GPA: 3.87

Wentworth Institute of Technology

College of Engineering and Technology
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Boston, MA

Sep 2011 – <u>Apr 2014</u>

GPA: 3.82

Tyumen, Russia

- Dean's List (2011-2014), graduated with honors: magna cum laude
- Tau Alpha Pi Honor Society, Applied Math minor, 2014 Annual Awards Recipient
- Wentworth Community Scholarship and Wentworth Merit Scholarship Recipient

University of Tyumen (transferred out)

Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science

Sep 2008 - May 2011

BS/MS in Mathematical Software and Information Systems Administration

- Full Tuition Scholarship
- 2008 Outstanding Incoming Class Award Recipient

CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, SEMINARS, AND HACKATHONS

- Visualforce Training (DEV450), Sep 2017 (Boston, MA)
- Hacking for Good @ HBS, Jun 2017 (Boston, MA)
- InformaticaWorld, May 2017 (San Francisco, CA)
- HackWITus @ WIT, Mar 2017 (Boston, MA Project: WebArm
- Progressive Web Apps @ Akamai, Mar 2017 (Cambridge, MA)
- AT&T WebRTC Boston Coding Workshop, May 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Future of Wearables Scramble™ @ Babson, Apr 2016 (Wellesley, MA)
- Salesforce World Tour, Apr 2016 & May 2017 (Boston, MA)
- Boston Code Camps (24 27), Nov 2015, 2016 & Mar 2016, 2017 (Cambridge, MA)
- Workday Higher Education Summit, Oct 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- Neotys North American User Conference, Oct 2015 (Boston, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2015 (Manchester, NH) Project: Conversion Wars Web App
- NeoLoad 3-day training, Feb 2015 (Waltham, MA)
- Mendix 3-day onsite training, Aug 2014; Laserfiche 4-day training, Sep 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2014 (Manchester, NH) Project: DWC Boy Scouts iOS App

VADIM MANOKHIN

vadim@manokhin.tech

VOLUNTEER SERVICE AND ACTIVITIES

Babson Entrepreneurial Thought & Action (ET&A) Award

Selection Committee Member

Babson Park, MA October 2016

Babson Undergraduate Commencement Babson Park, MA

Commencement Host May 2016 & 2017

Wentworth Admissions Office Boston, MA

Admissions Blogger Jan 2014 – Apr 2014

Wentworth Career Services Boston, MA

Web Application Developer May 2013 – Apr 2014

Wentworth International Student Services Boston, MA

International Student Ambassador Aug 2012 – Apr 2014

Wentworth President's Host Society

President's Host Feb 2012 – Apr 2014

- Represented the Institute at various events, on and off campus

- Served as an ambassador of public relations in various supporting roles

- Promoted Wentworth's academic programs, services and student activities

Wentworth Community Partnership

Boston, MA

Boston, MA

Alternative Spring Break Volunteer

Mar 2012

- Focused on environmental work in the Biscayne and the Everglades National Parks, FL
- Worked with wounded birds at the Florida Keys Wild Bird Sanctuary, FL
- Worked with animals at Florida Monkey Forest Zoo, Key Largo, FL

Wentworth Counseling Center & Disability Services Partnership

English II Note Taker for a Disabled Student

Boston, MA

Oct 2011 - Dec 2011

AFFILIATIONS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

- I've been a member of TAΠ (<u>Tau Alpha Pi</u>, Massachusetts Alpha Chapter), the professional honor society for engineering technology, since 2013.
- Occasionally, I participate in the local Boston technology meetups, hackathons, and user group activities such as <u>BNT</u> (Boston New Technology), <u>Boston AUG</u> (Atlassian User Group), <u>Code</u> <u>for Boston</u> Hack Nights, and others.
- Outside of my day-to-day duties as a developer I enjoy cycling, creating and playing music, learning new things, and generally expanding my horizons.